MEHUL JOSHI

- @ m1vjoshi@gmail.com
- h (425) 943-1672
- a 19311 25th AVE SE, Bothell, Washington 98012

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a self-directed and motivated student developer with experience working effectively in dynamic environments. I am fluent in Java, Python, and Javascript programming languages. I have an innate ability to design and create software that helps people in a myriad of ways.

SKILLS

- · Application design
- Creative self-starter
- Originality
- Fast learner
- Sales expertise

EDUCATION

North Creek High School Bothell, WA • 2019

High School Diploma

University of Washington Seattle, WA • 2023 Bachelor of Science

CERTIFICATIONS

Responsive Web Design (FreeCodeCamp.org): Given to those individuals who finish 6 programming projects in HTML and CSS to make responsive websites. Approximate time of completion: 300 hours

JavaScript Data Structures and Algorithms (FreeCodeCamp.org): Given to those individuals who master over 300+ hours of Javascript work. Approximate time of completion: 300 hours.

WORK HISTORY

Interactive Math Academy - Python And Math Tutor Bellevue, Washington • 06/2019 - Current

- Explained math concepts in caring and encouraging environment to help kids thrive and learn.
- Helped grow the understanding of python for middle schoolers in a effective way.

Self-Employeed - Freelance Computer Science Tutor

Bothell, Washington • 09/2016 - Current
I taught and basic Java to my fellow peers that were taking AP CS A. For this role I did all of my own advertising, planning, and marketing.

Self-Employeed - Lead Designer For Wooden Box Company Bothell, Washington • 06/2016 - 09/2018

 Worked with industry standards to make a better solution for expensive wooden raised planter beds.

Self-Employeed - Paver Designer And Installer Bothell, Washington • 05/2016 - 07/2018

- Utilized knowledge of carpentry and general construction to complete attractive finish work.
- Operated tools, equipment and machinery according to safety standards.
- · Worked with all types of weather and ground conditions.
- · Calculated materials and time needed for each job.

PROJECTS

- Dofleini Chess (https://github.com/csmjoshi/Chess):
 An intuitive way to play chess in today's chaotic world. Play with a friend, foe, or computer for fun.
- Digit Recognizer (private repository):

This was one of my first projects in Computer Vision. It takes tons of hand written digit data and with a neural network it predicts which digit is the given digit.

• Cancer prediction model (private repository): Implemented a neural network that takes in the size of a tumor, shape of a tumor along with many other factors and predicts if it is cancerous or not.